<reactionSuite projectile="n" target="Pu-239" formatVersion="GND 1.7" library="Estimated experimental data and covariances" version="0.1" projectileFrame="lab"><styles><exp_unc name="estimated experimental uncertainty" date="2026-07-16"/></styles><documentations><documentation name="DS6006_Pu-239_cs">EXFOR No. = wip; the data are not yet in GMA, following the current numbering 	and convention, I would assign D6006; Journal article = A. Sanchez-Caballero, D. Cano-Ott,     E. Mendoza, et al. (2025). The data used in here are all provided in private communication by N. Otsuka.  	on behalf of the n_TOF collaboration for the Neutron Data Standards and will be soon in EXFOR.
  - Given their write-up, I treat the data as shape ratios. At the Standards meeting in January 2026, we decided to take only the data above 150 keV and treat them as ratios to 235U because the flux was measured in the energy range as ratios to 235U(n,f) cross sections and assuming the 2018 Standard for the 235U(n,f) cross sections.
- I assume the detector efficiency uncertainty of 0.5% drops out because it is a normalization uncertainty that would have been taken care of by the normalization, but as we take the data as shape, it does not apply.
- The angular distribution and forward-boost uncertainty is energy-dependent and as such does apply to shape data. Given their answer, I add in an angular distribution and forward-boost uncertainty that is 0% up to 3 MeV and then linearly rises to 2% up to 10 MeV. I assume that the effect of sample thickness is negligible given their write-up and add no uncertainty.
- No extra uncertainty is added on the neutron flux because it is their systematic uncertainty. The neutron flux uncertainty includes the Standard uncertainty. So, I need to reduce it for that.
- I assume background uncertainties for now to be 0% per the guidance of n_TOF authors. However, note that we are just investigating with fissionTPC folks the likelihood of thermal background. Could a similar thermal background apply to them? Or is that highly unlikely because they have a much longer flight path &gt;100 m versus 100 cm for fissionTPC? Roberto Capote wrote that they use the calorimeter and shield their detector with cadmium or boron, not recall which one, so no thermal background.
- I assume they don&#8217;t have a wrap-around background? (lowest-energy neutrons from the preceding pulse are overlapping with the fastest neutrons from the current pulse.) Roberto Capote confirmed that they have no wrap-around background.
- They only address in their answer neutron attenuation and multiple scattering in the sample but not in the surrounding. This is especially relevant as this is not a clean-ratio measurement, where U-235 is in the same chamber, but rather in different detectors where they might see a beam more distorted by neutron scattering. The key question is how far away are the neutron monitor measurements? Is there a lot of material? Right now, I would add my typical template values of 0.2-2%.
- I believe them on deadtime uncertainty being 0.
- I add a negligibly small impurity uncertainty of 0.01% (this corresponds to their sample purity of 99.9%). This is not fully correlated as the different isotopes have energy-dependent cross sections and corrections.
- Per authors, the energy resolution is 0.042% at 100 keV to 0.058% around 1 MeV. I would assume that they have a fine energy resolution until 100 keV and then getting increasingly worse above. So, I leave 0.042% until 100 keV, increase linearly to 0.058% at 1 MeV and then keep it at 0.058% above 1 MeV. </documentation></documentations></reactionSuite>