<reactionSuite projectile="n" target="Pu-239" formatVersion="GND 1.7" library="Estimated experimental data and covariances" version="0.1" projectileFrame="lab"><styles><exp_unc name="estimated experimental uncertainty" date="2026-07-17"/></styles><documentations><documentation name="DS8002_Pu-239_cs">EXFOR No. = 14271.003; in GMA the data have the data set numbers 8002; Journal article = 	F. Tovesson et al., NSE 165, 224 (2010) (Pu-9); F. Tovesson et al., NSE 159, 94 (2008;) 	All data are taken from EXFOR.  The statistical unc. is explicitly given in EXFOR. The U-235 	background reduction uncertainty is explicitly given in  EXFOR. I assume it to be Gaussian 	correlated.The Pu-239 background reduction uncertainty is explicitly given in EXFOR. I 	assume it to be Gaussian correlated. The normalization uncertainty was defined by comparison 	to the thermal cross section ratio and therefore completely different than from any other 	measurement. It was not included in the GMA uncertainty estimate. It is fully correlated. All 	data points in that measurement are from the WNR measurement and therefore, only time 	resolution and TOF length uncertainties apply for this part of the measurement. The  	uncertainty on the residual detector efficiency uncertainty is given in the Np-237 	paper and accounts for different thresholds for Pu-9 and U-235. I assume a full correlation. 	The deadtime uncertainty is given in the Np-237 paper. I assume a full correlation. 	No impurity uncertainty is given. I assume the value provided by Kyle Schmitt calculated 	for that level of contamination. I assume full correlation. No angular distribution 	uncertainty is provided. I assume 0.1%. I assume it to be Gaussian correlated following 	the template. Given the high Einc, this could actually be a larger uncertainty. No  	attenuation uncertainty was given, so I assume the uncertainty by the template. Fredrik  	mentioned that he reduced the attenuation effect in his paper by careful design. So, a small 	uncertainty should be ok. I assume it to be Gaussian correlated. The multiple scattering  	uncertainty is reduced in ratio measurement according to the template. Here, I assume  	something which seems reasonable until Fredrik gets back to me. All in all well documented on 	unc. but only statunc and background unc. made it into GMA. So, my estimate will be significantly 	higher.  Fredrik thinks my assumption are reasonable (communication by e-mail Feb. 2018).</documentation></documentations></reactionSuite>