<reactionSuite projectile="n" target="Pu-239" formatVersion="GND 1.7" library="Estimated experimental data and covariances" version="0.1" projectileFrame="lab"><styles><exp_unc name="estimated experimental uncertainty" date="2026-07-17"/></styles><documentations><documentation name="DS6002_Pu-239_cs">EXFOR No. = 14851002; the data are not yet in GMA, following the current numbering 	and convention, I would assign D6002; Journal article = Dongwi et al., Nuclear Data Sheets, Vol.202, p.30 (2025). 	The data used in here are all provided by EXFOR. The incident neutron energy is supplied in the form of a lower and upper bin edge. 	ARIADNE as well as GMA cannot deal with that. Instead, an Einc per each data value needs to  	be supplied. I take the mid-point of the energy bin as this one-point energy. This procedure  	was discussed with L. Snyder in private communication and he agreed that this is  	acceptable. The data are absolute Pu-239(n,f)/U-235(n,f) data. They were normalized with     their own procedure but are systematically off by 2% compared to ENDF/B-VIII.0     which they do not fully trust because of issues in space charge and thermal background that    remain unresolved. I added 0.85% and 0.75% normalization unc. for those as they would be constant.    The statistical uncertainty is explicitly supplied by the experimentalist and the     correlation matrix is assumed to be diagonal. The first detector efficiency uncertainty     is the "variational" unc. which accounts for the variation in the PID cuts. The     correlation matrix is constant with a factor of 0.15 in a visual comparison with     that option of ARIADNE and the partial correlation matrix provided by L. Snyder     (not perfect). The background uncertainty accounts for background correction uncertainties  	related to the wrap-around background. Background due to fission fragment recoils and alpha-	particles is zero because they are clearly identified by PID cuts. The unc. in the variation  	of the PID cut is the variational unc. The correlation matrix provided by L. Snyder is  	best approximated with a diagonal one in a visual comparison with that option of ARIADNE     and the partial correlation matrix provided by L. Snyder. The second efficiency uncertainty     accounts for uncertainties in the efficiency model such as in the SRIM stopping power assumption,    FY unc., etc., The correlation matrix is on average diagonal in a visual comparison with the partial 	correlation matrix provided by L. Snyder in private communication. Correlations to other  	measurements could arise because of common usage of SRIM. However, the correlation matrix is  	diagonal to begin with. Even if it was not diagonal, only low Einc would be correlated due to 	common usage of SRIM according to a discussion with R. Casperson (U-8/U-5). The impurity uncertainty  	accounts for contaminations in the sample. The correlation matrix is correlated with a factor of 0.35 in a  	visual comparison with the data provided by L. Snyder. This uncertainty could be  	correlated to other measurements due to usage of alpha-counting and related nuclear data. 	No normalization unc. needs to be accounted for as this is treated as a shape measurement. Attenuation 	and multiple scattering uncertainties are provided by L. Snyder and are diagonal (MC statistics,    only, no nuclear data unc. considered}. The FF angular     distribution uncertainty is part of the detector efficiency uncertainty. The energy     uncertainty is obtained by accounting for the TOF length unc. and trsl which is provided     in the journal article. The dead time uncertainty is zero according to L. Snyder    due to improved electronics. The beam-sample-overlap uncertainty is explicitly given     and provided by L. Snyder. It is energy-dependent and nearly diagonal, because it     was corrected with a measurement. Private communication took place by phone meeting    and e-mail exchange in the time-frame from late summer of 2025 to Oct. of    2025, L. Snyder was involved in that exchange.</documentation></documentations></reactionSuite>