<reactionSuite projectile="n" target="Pu-239" formatVersion="GND 1.7" library="Estimated experimental data and covariances" version="0.1" projectileFrame="lab"><styles><exp_unc name="estimated experimental uncertainty" date="2026-07-17"/></styles><documentations><documentation name="nubar_Marini2021_Pu-239_nubar-prompt">EXFOR No. = 14799002. Journal article = Marini,    et al., to be submitted to PRL. Uncertainties called out by Paola: multiple     scattering, limited Eout range (extrapolation), limited coverage of angular     distributions. Explicitly given uncertainties: energy uncertainties, extrapolation,     angular distribution, wrap-around background uncertainties.     Uncertainties that are missing and I asked about: random coincidences.     Gamma background uncertainties. Impurity uncertainties. Multiple-scattering     uncertainties. The impurity level of Cf-252 was such that no impurity unc.     apply. The purity level Pu-239 is 99.9% (rest Pu-240) comparable to Conde who     cites  0.2% unc. Julien states 0.01% impact. I take the middle ground of 0.1%.     They correct random coincidences by randomly triggering a gate and measuring it     and claim no uncertainty. Zero unc. in this correction is not supported by literature.     I take the template value. They apply the same gamma cuts to Pu-239 and Cf-252,     which also cut out some neutrons because they really want to get out gammas.     I think that could bias the PFNS and there is also a difference between gammas     from Pu-239 than from Cf-252. So, there is a remaining unc. I take the template     value. Data are cut above 20 MeV after private communication with Paoal who wrote:     We corrected for the forward boost of FF when accounting for the angular     distribution of neutrons. However I have to mention that, as we do not     measure Eout&gt;14MeV, we trust our nubar values up to 20MeV Ein. Above     this energy the pre-equilibrium emission w/ n above 14MeV becomes     significant, so you should consider the nubar values only as a lower limit.    I take multiple scattering unc. at unc. of 0.2% as Paola said the unc. are     similar in size. As should be obvious from the discussion above private     communication with authors took place.</documentation></documentations></reactionSuite>