<reactionSuite projectile="n" target="U-235" formatVersion="GND 1.7" library="Estimated experimental data and covariances" version="0.1" projectileFrame="lab"><styles><exp_unc name="estimated experimental uncertainty" date="2026-07-17"/></styles><documentations><documentation name="DS6008_U-235_cs">EXFOR No. = 23675.002; Journal article = A. Manna et al. Physics Letters B 860 (2025) 139213.
- Given their write-up, I treat the data as absolute without any ratios as they measure relative to 1H(n,n) cs. At the Standards meeting, it was decided: "Denise: to put the 235U(n,f) cs of Manna and Priovano into CRD file as 235U(n,f) absolute cs and put in the CRD file of Manna/ Pirovano what 1H(n,n) angular distributions were used for the Manna/ Pirovano data as tabulated by Naohiko in EXFOR (and angles in the comment). "
- Background could be missing for thermalized neutrons hitting the fission chamber, they do quantify the C-12 background for the monitor measurement and alpha/ gamma background via PSD for their fission chamber measurement. Elisa thinks this should not be an issue because the bunches are separated enough, but I worry more about random coincicdences. It should likely be a small effect in any way. Elisa wrote: "The alpha/gamma discrimination is made with the amplitude spectra, since the FFs and light particle have really different energy deposition in the detector (all confirmed by simulations)." and "We are working in the high energy region and the bunches are well spaced between them, so the thermal neutrons arrive well before the next bunch and do not overlap."
- Forward-boost, angular distriution and stopping power were MC simulated.
- Sample non-uniformity was measured and folded with beam overlap. Seems well-done.
- Multiple scattering seems to be part of background as part of blank measurement. I would add a small uncertainty. Elisa wrote: "We simulated transmission through fission detectors and PE samples. &#160;The estimated uncertainty for this ranges from 0.2% to 0.5%." I added 0.4%.
- Quantified uncertainties: neutron flux, statistics, detector efficiency, normalization, deadtime, impurity. Missing was multiple scattering, which Elisa provided in private communication.
</documentation></documentations></reactionSuite>